No arrangement is more beautiful … or more complicated.
A Late Quartet is a music, drama film directed by Yaron Zilberman.
When the beloved cellist of a world-renowned string quartet is diagnosed with a life threatening illness, the group's future suddenly hangs in the
balance as suppressed emotions, competing egos and uncontrollable passions threaten to derail years of friendship and collaboration.
As they are about to play their 25th anniversary concert — quite possibly their last —
only their intimate bond and the power of music can preserve their legacy.
Peter Mitchell, played by Christopher Walken.
Robert Gelbart, played by Philip Seymour Hoffman.
Daniel Lerner, played by Mark Ivanir.
Juliette Gelbart, played by Catherine Keener.
Alexandra Gelbart, played by Imogen Poots.
Pilar, played by Liraz Charhi.
A Late Quartet (released in Australia as Performance) is a 2012 American drama film
directed by Yaron Zilberman and co-written by Zilberman and Seth Grossman.
The film stars Philip Seymour Hoffman, Christopher Walken,
Catherine Keener, Mark Ivanir and Imogen Poots.
Inspired by and structured around Beethoven's Op.
131, the film follows the world-renowned Fugue String Quartet after its cellist
Peter Mitchell (Walken) is diagnosed with Parkinson's disease.
Frederick Elmes served as cinematographer and
Angelo Badalamenti composed the score.
The Brentano String Quartet played the quartet music for the soundtrack and Anne Sofie von Otter appears
as the cellist's late wife, singing Korngold's "Marietta's Song" from Die tote Stadt.
The film premiered in the Special Presentation program at the 2012 Toronto
International Film Festival, and was theatrically released in over 30 countries.
It received generally positive reviews.
The tone is emotional.